The former boss of Royal Bank of Scotland is recognised in the new year’s honours list in a move sure to anger small businesses mistreated by the state-controlled bank.

Ross McEwan, a New Zealander who ran RBS for six years, is made a Commander of the British Empire for services to the financial sector.

RBS returned to profit under Mr McEwan, cut government ownership from 78 to 62 per cent and resolved historical problems, including paying fines to US authorities for mis-selling mortgage bonds in the run-up to the financial crisis.

Mr McEwan, 62, was paid £3.6 million at RBS last year and left in October to take up the top job at National Australia Bank. The government’s decision to honour Mr McEwan will anger…

Continue reading